Preeti Chachlani

1200 E Hillsdale Blvd. Foster City California 94404 • Linkedin • (641) 781-0922 • chachlani@wisc.edu

CAREER PROFILE

Analyst with an MBA and MA Economics (Quantitative Methods +Health Policy). Worked in the financial domain for 8 years before making a switch to healthcare domain. Have been working as a data analyst in education and healthcare domains for almost 2 years

SKILLS

SAS, R, Stata, SAS Viya, MS-Excel

EXPERIENCE

Institute for Research on Poverty, University of Wisconsin-Madison

Data Scientist, 01/2021-till date

- Providing data management and analysis support to Medicaid Evaluation, Research and Technical Assistance (MERTA) project
- Programming Medicaid claims and enrollment data in SAS
- Developing standard workflows and composing technical reports

The Sphere Institute, California

Data and Policy Analyst II, 11/2019-10/2020

- Conducted data investigations and statistical analyses for CMS utilizing SAS
- · Manipulated and summarized Medicare Parts A, B and D claims data to produce statistical results
- Wrote flexible SAS macros and generated reports
- Created Excel workbooks/ PowerPoints/word documents to interpret and present the results of the investigations
- Created visual dashboards using SAS Viya
- Maintained data dictionary and metadata

Georgia Department of Early Care & Learning, Georgia

Data Analyst Intern, 01/2019-05/2019

- Modeled data using advanced excel functions: VLOOKUPS, Pivots, Advanced Charting and Excel Macros
- Translated data into key performance metrics, created figures in Tableau and presented in PowerPoint
- Researched and responded to daily quantitative research inquiries from the policy team
- Used VBA to create a macro that can easily calculate and format the routine daily and monthly reports

Georgia State University, Georgia

Graduate Research Assistant, 08/2017-05/2019

Research Paper, Effects of the ACA Medicaid on self-reported Health Outcomes

- Analyzed results of public surveys, such as the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System (BRFSS), with an eye toward ACA Medicaid expansion impacts on self-reported health in the past 7 years
- Used Stata for cleaning the BRFSS data and implemented difference-in-difference model for analysis

Data Mining Project

- Implemented logistic regression techniques on 284,000 observations to predict likelihood of car accident fatalities
- Curated data to conduct exploratory data analysis, cleaning, and pre-model analysis in SAS.

State Bank of India

Senior Analyst, Deputy Manager, 01/2009-07/2017

- Started as an Analyst, Assistant Manager at Junior Management level
- Got fast track promotion to the Middle Management Grade by outscoring >1000 officers at equivalent grade in an academic exam

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Economics (Quantitative Methods)	May 2019
Georgia State University	GPA 4.15/4.30
Master of Business Administration, Finance and Marketing	June 2009
Faculty of Management Studies, Maharishi Dayanand Saraswati University	GPA: 4.0/4.0
Bachelor of Arts, Economics (Honors) and Mathematics	May 2007
Sophia College	GPA: 4.0/4.0

AWARDS

• The Mark E. Schaefer Economics Award, Georgia State University

Outstanding Graduate Student Award, Georgia State University

April 2019

December 2018